so this is our first podcast from
another country you're gonna have to
believe us but we're in San Francisco we
we've been traveling around we've done a
lot of interviews with a lot of people
we've got a few ideas for some new
documentaries and we're gonna show you a
picture now at the rebel wisdom 'mobile
and yeah let you know some of the people
that we've been seeing so we've seen a
Kyra the Don he's got some amazing plans
for an intellectual dark web Marvel
Cinematic Universe so intellectual
darkwave we've seen Jordan Greenhalgh
Daniel Shmack Tim burger is kind of
next-level futurist kind of guy and also
as insisted by our supporters in the LA
after our last podcast Paul Van der clay
a pastor who's done a lot of stuff about
Jordan Pederson we went to see a couple
of days ago and we went to one of his
services as well yeah one of his sermons
so he filmed some of his sermon we
filmed a really good interview with him
so huge amounts of content coming up and
for this podcast we're also going to
talk about psychedelics because today in
particular why don't you to say who we
saw today yeah so today was Jim Fadiman
who is one of the basically as known as
the the father of micro dosing he's
really I would say a psychedelic elder
he's been around you know doing research
really from the beginning and micro
dosing in particular has become very
popular and really beneficial for a lot
of people in terms of creativity but
also in terms of people using it for
anxiety and depression so it was really
really interesting conversation and a
lovely man as well and then we saw Eric
Davis who is one of my favorite thinkers
actually Eric Davis he describes himself
as having a PhD in high weirdness but
his his PhD is actually in religious
studies and he really looks at the
intersection between technology and kind
of the religious impulse and tribes and
subcultures very you know one of his
famous books is called tech gnosis so
it's a really interesting kind of
intersection
between all those ideas it's kind of
about how the religious impulse comes up
through technology and it's kind of a
big part of yeah the tech subculture
yeah so and I think yeah we want to sort
of fill in the gaps explain why
so we've now done we did the Michael
Pollan interview which we called the
psychedelic Renaissance about three
weeks ago and then we did an interview
with Jamie Weil who is a flow state
expert also talks a lot about
psychedelics and this is something that
we have yeah it's a big interest of ours
we both got kind of a history with the
psychedelic festival breakin convention
and it's one of those areas of real kind
of a sense of sort of possibility for
shifting ways of thinking and shifting
culture and I think that's why we're
interested in it and especially there's
a lot of talk right now and I guess
we're both firm believers in the
importance of being able to move beyond
ideology to have generative
conversations you know something
starting to see in the intellectual
darkweb it seems absolutely essential if
we're going to find direction in the
kind of chaotic times we live in and
psychedelics more than any other thing I
know about our deconditioning agents and
decondition ideology incredibly well
however they can go both ways and so
that's that's part of the really
interesting synchronicity is that
Michael Pollan's book has come out and
really bringing to the mainstream for
maybe not for the first time but in a in
a very new way the the power of these
substances and so the other questions
are how does one use them correctly and
how yeah how do we navigate it because
obviously you know we're sitting right
now in San Francisco and in the late 60s
there really was a massive mainstreaming
of psychedelics that didn't go all that
well it had its benefit it had massive
downfalls as well so you know that's
kind of an open question I guess we've
been asking people about and toying with
ourselves is how do we use them most
effectively moving forward
yeah we're literally about
half a mile from Haight Ashbury from
literally the intersection of Haight
Ashbury which was ground zero for the
60s and the interesting question because
we've talked about kind of ideological
fixation and the interesting question is
they were counter cultural agents in the
60s kind of the 1950s and 1960s there
there was a very sort of firm cultural
kind of traditionalist culture and they
were what they were one of the big
things that challenged that so the
question that we're asking is are they
still deconditioning agents or is
because the ideology that we're in
nowadays is a very different kind of
ideology and I think we've all we we've
we've done a lot of films and a lot of
conversations about the nature of this
new ideology are they still those kind
of deconditioning agents given the fact
that the new ideology is is much more
the ideology that actually emerged from
the 60s and we could argue we do argue
has kind of become corrupt
it started we've used kembers work quite
a lot talking about it started as a very
positive development that what he calls
the green meme which is equality and and
relativism and listening to other voices
and including marginalized perspectives
that is a good thing but then it became
corrupt and became an ideology in its
own right and do psychedelics still play
the same role that now that they played
then yeah and as we've been kind of
asking people about it and I'm thinking
about it as well and even as you're
talking I'm I'm sorry I'm kind of
inquiring into that myself am i yeah
actually I do think that they can still
decondition from any ideology you know
if you if you look at shamanism
throughout history psychedelics have
been used for war they've been used for
peace they've been used to heal they've
been used to harm the you know Jim
Fadiman who who we saw today is a big
proponent of a real core aspect of
psychedelic usage which is setting and
set so setting is where you are always
that set is what you're bringing to it
yourself and those two things can really
have a big big impact
on it so in a sense you know part of the
interesting one interesting question is
how do we create the kind of setting and
set now moving forward where a lot more
people probably going to try
psychedelics that's conducive to moving
away from ideology rather than deeper in
to the ideology we're in now because
that could happen and that would be not
a good thing yeah because we my question
to Michael Pollan was is your book a
moment where psychedelics become
mainstream and he kind of said that it
was and pretty much everyone we've
spoken to since we've been here have a
group has agreed that yes this is a very
significant moment New York Times
best-selling writer has written a
best-selling book about psychedelic
therapy people are people who have never
tried psychedelics are saying wow I'm
interested to try this it definitely is
that crossover point so we've kind of
been part of this conversation for I
guess 10 years or so I first did a story
about psychedelic therapy back in 2008
you've been part of the breakin
convention Festival for a long time so I
guess what we're interested in doing is
is pushing that conversation on ok.now
the mainstream starting to recognize the
value of psychedelics okay fine
but what that in itself is not that's
not the end point the end point like I
I've always been very frustrated with
the psychedelic community of almost like
fetishizing the psychedelic experience
and not learning the deeper lessons of a
psychedelic experience which even going
back to Aldous Huxley was psychedelics
cleanse the doors of perception but you
see things so they remove a lot of
filters so you see a lot of things more
true to how they are how do you how do
we start to live in that space how do we
start to live beyond the psychedelic
experience and not just kind of psycho
yeah fetishize the drug and fetishize
that state of mind and actually work on
because I I firmly believe and this has
been absolutely true for me that we have
to do the inner work psychedelics we get
a few freebies we get
you kind of insights into how things
could be beyond our conditioning beyond
wow I'm one with the universe I I know
what my true nature is all that sort of
stuff and it's like yes great true but
it's an ever decreasing circle if you
keep just doing the drug without doing
the inner work to really identify the
blocks in yourself that stop you being
in that space no not necessarily all the
time but what are the things that are
stopping you from from being in that
state of flow in the rest of your life
yeah and this is something that so in
the last breakin convention happens
every two years and the last two so
starting in 2013 I think this has been
the topic I've written and I'm spoken
about which is I've called a psychedelic
Shadow it's this idea that well so in
kind of summary you can take
psychedelics for 20 years and be having
these peak experiences which I would
call vertical that's kind of up and down
and you can still Jim Philemon put it
nicely you can still want to kill
someone when they cut you off when
you're driving and you can still you
know here he also had a nice example
it's like you you love everything but I
hate my parents you know so there's
something missing there this is
something I started to see first in
myself and then what actually helped me
kind of get out of it a bit was having a
really dark experience and encountering
my shadow and realizing oh it's not all
love and light
so what I've kind of I'm loosely
developing is is a model I call train
trip integrate which is the idea that
not you don't just need the horizontal
you need what you were just talking
about the sorry of the vertical you need
the horizontal as well and the
horizontal is the kind of work so work
where you and you you work with other
people it kind of did various types of
therapy bodywork meditation a lot of
different ways of understanding yourself
and how you relate to other people to
get away from the potential narcissism
and away from the potential lack of
development that comes with just
tripping and tripping and tripping and
that is something that the psychedelic
community I think needs to really look
or something Jaime will was talking
about and I think what he said that was
really really interesting that really
struck a chord with me was that you know
he he's traditionally come from the kind
of ecstatic those ecstatic moments and
how do you get into that kind of place
and how does that then lead to being in
a flow State
Jordan Peterson is really bringing up
the catharsis the lower levels that's
all hard one kind of feels this kind of
deep practical wisdom and it really
feels like that's been missing from the
psychedelic world it's all you know a
lot of the time it's all love and light
and crystals and bollocks like that and
what it needs is the real encounter with
the shadow and on that point that's
that's one of the the points I made in
what I wrote breaking invention is that
the traditions like meditation they
don't generally look at the shadow in
the traditional uses something Ken
Wilber Wilber points out you can
meditate for 50 years as well and still
be a massive asshole because you're not
looking at the sides of yourself that
you reject necessarily so you need
something or some combination of
practices that allows you to own your
shadow allows you to know how to connect
with other people in a way and have
reflection on yourself and then also
allows you to break into spaces where
you think differently and where you can
break free from your constricted thought
structures so the point being it's not
as simple as people just taking
psychedelics a lot more has to go into
it yeah I just had a sort of thought
truth is a psychedelic truth is a
psychedelic experience and this is
something that Jordan Peterson talks
about that aligning oneself with the
truth is is what that's the deepest
story of Western culture that's the
logos and magical things happen when we
align ourselves with the truth I'd never
really framed it in that way but that
has certainly been my journey since I
did a lot of psychedelics at university
and found it a really awakening
experience at first but I went through
that experience of ever decreasing
circles and actually it took me quite a
long time to recover from that sort of
chasing that high and feeling I kind of
coined the phrase living in the shadow
of myself
getting this sort of sense of who I
could be beyond all of this stuff just a
stuff that we live in on a daily basis
and chasing that high and chasing that
experience but then always coming down
and and still still really struggling
with with various things and it almost
it being worse because I had a taste of
what it would have been like without all
of the kind of the day-to-day stuff and
it wasn't until I started doing a lot of
personal growth work you know work that
I then started to kind of identify those
places in myself okay this is where I
shut down this is where I've got this
kind of swing between grandiosity and
worthlessness and all of these
personality patterns that yeah I got
from my parents I got from my yeah all
of this other boring individual stuff
that we all have that kind of keeps us
trapped in some ways and it was only by
doing all of that inner work that I
really started to kind of align all
those parts of myself and it the space
that opens up for me you know in a
workshop of sort of five or six days but
I'm really sort of speaking my truth and
really like dredging stuff off I'm
really identifying it is a psychedelic
experience and the risk of kind of
giving a plug for our workshops that is
what comes in with two or three days in
a workshop experience you find a lot of
these yeah it becomes this very powerful
transformative where you can feel that
you can feel in in in the room like that
that level of what truth magic it's it's
it's a similar space and so it's a flow
state in that sense yeah and yeah that's
a really nice point because for me and
and for people who do psychedelic
therapy professionally as well the truth
is absolutely the key element of the
experience that's that's curative
because you can't hide on a psychedelic
you can't hide from yourself and the
truth is inner truth it's not so much
the truth of this is how the universe is
all constructed because you can't really
share that with other people you know
it's about your your own inner truth so
it's around you know
phenomenologically you're sitting and
something's coming up some kind of
negative feeling and you have to
acknowledge and go into it it's like
this is true you might not want it to be
true but it's true it's happening and
whatever is coming up psychologically is
true for you it you know and whatever it
is in psychedelic therapy they always
say go into it you know my wife is
currently training as a sitter in one of
the studies and they say in the training
you know someone might be experiencing
serious paranoia and what they say is
great go into it go on right into the
paranoia get parent you know real and
they're you know they're holding you in
a context probably not yeah no that is
the way you deal with it that is the way
you go into it it's this real love of
the truth and you have to kind of have
that same attitude in a psychedelic
experience or in a workshop experience
yeah and very much gym Fatima was saying
that today so yeah to kind of wrap this
up the we're thinking about we're
definitely going to continue doing a lot
of interviews with psychedelic therapist
psychedelic thinkers because this is
yeah this is this is an area that we're
both interested in and we both think has
got a real value for for the culture
yeah so and then just some final
housekeeping to close we've started
using the community tab at long last so
if you want to keep up with with what
we're up to and what content is coming
up on the channel go on that tab and
we've already posted a couple things
from the trip and then also this podcast
due to popular demand is going to be
audio only as well as video only so
we're gonna have that set up you wanna
have a look at us yeah well have they're
ready to set up for this podcast and
then all the previous ones will be on
there as well